TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
왔다!
It's here!
어이, 어이!
Hey, hey!
긴카이 씨입니까?
Are you Mr. Ginkai?
어, 어!
Uh, yeah!
그럼 전 여기서 실례하겠습니다.
Then I will be going now.
당신의 활약, 도련님이 진심으로 기대하고 있습니다.
The young master is really looking forwards to your future great activities.
이게 본체.
This is the main body.
이게 탄약.
These are ammo.
이거... 이게...
This... This must be...
데스 메달! 고맙다, 코쿠류!
The Death Medal! Thank you, Kokuryu!
폭주! 신형 메타비
Reckless Run! New Type Metabee
(en: Kilobots Rising)
메다로트 사 이벤트 홀
Medarot Company Event Hall
알고 계시는 대로, 메다로트는 틴펫이라고 불리우는 기본 구조에, 파트를 장착해서 로봇 배틀, 즉 로보틀을 위한 고성능 로봇입니다.
As you already know, Medarot is a high performance robot, made of base frame called Tinpet
and additional parts, for robot battle, or in short, Robattle.
메다로트인 두뇌인 메달이 떨어져 나오면, 기능 정지입니다. 패배의 증표네요.
When the medal, the brain of Medarot, falls off, it stops working. It is a proof of a defeat.
로보틀은 여러분 메다로터가 메다로트에게 정확한 지시를 내리지 않으면 좋은 싸움은 불가능합니다.
In a Robattle, a Medarotter must give precise commands to his Medarot, or a proper fight is near to impossible.
메다로트와의 커뮤니케이션에 빠질 수 없는 필수 아이템이라고 하면, 그렇죠! 메다롯치입니다!
And what's the indispensable item for the communication with Medarot? You got it - it's Medarotch!
그래서 메다로트 사가 지금까지보다도 더욱 로보틀을 재미있게 하기 위해서 개발한 것이
That's why Medarot Company decided to make a Robattle more exciting by developing
내일 발매되는 메다롯치 어드밴스입니다!
Medarotch Advance,
좋아! 오래 기다리고 있었어요!
Alright! I've waiting for that!
빨리 보여줘!
Hurry up and show us!
거들먹거리지 말고!
And stop putting it on airs!
니들 조용히 좀 해!
Be quiet, you two!
메다롯치 어드밴스의 등장입니다!
Medarot Advanced is here!
현재 있는 버전보다도 업그레이드된 최첨단...
It's a cutting-edge upgraded version of the currently available...
아가씨, 저, 저기...
Miss, you know...
스테이지에는 올라오면 안 돼.
Please don't come up to the stage.
아리카 멍청이. 저널리스트라니 정말 어처구니가 없군!
Arika, you dolt! I can't believe you're a journalist!
이와노이, 카가미야마, 잔뜩 웃어 줘라!
Iwanoi and Kagamiyama, have a good laugh at her!
저널리스트는 가끔은 위험을 무릅쓰기도 하는 거야!
A journalist sometimes risk danger!
계속해도 괜찮니?
Can I continue?
네...
Yes...
전송 속도도 전보다 30배 업!
Transportation speed is 30 times of before!
메다로트가 보고 있는 걸 직접 볼 수 있는 버추얼 아이 탑재!
It has Virtual Eye feature that lets you see thorugh your Medarot's eyes!
자, 손님을 바라보아!
Look at the audiences.
뒤의 스크린에는 버추얼 아이의 영상에 비추어집니다.
The video from Virtual Eye is on the screen back there.
어?
Huh?
재밌다!
Interesting!
야, 우리 스크린에 떴어!
Hey, we're on the screen!
이걸로 메다롯치 어드밴스의 발표를 마치겠습니다.
And that'll conclude the announcement of Medarotch Advanced.
나 오늘 여러 의미로 자기혐오.
I think I'm going to hate myself today for reasons.
알아.
I understand you.
신형 메다로치! 그 버추얼 아이인가 하는 기능 대단해!
New Medarotch! That Virtual Eye feature was really great!
그래, 그게 우리 손에 들어온다면 우리 더욱 강해질 거야!
Yeah, if we get that, we'll get even stronger!
빨리 내일이 되면 좋겠다. 어서 사러 가고 싶어!
I hope it becomes tomorrow soon. I want to go buy it right now!
예약권이나 잃어버리지 마라, 멍청이 아리카.
Don't lose your preorder ticket, Arika the dolt.
예약권?
Preorder ticket?
어?
Huh?
예약 안 했냐?
Didn't you preorder one?
안 했는데?
I didn't.
이와노이, 카가미야마, 알려 줘라!
Iwanoi and Kagamiyama! Tell him!
잇키, 잘 들어! 신형 메다롯치는 발매 전부터 대단한 인기로 지금 예약하면 3개월은 기다려야 할 거야.
Ikki, listen! New Medarotch is so popular already before the release date,
so if you preorder one now, then you're gonna wait 3 months!
그러니까, 넌 낙엽의 계절까지 메다로치 없으심이다!
That means you won't get one until the season of fallen leaves!
저런...
No way...
뭐, 포기해. 너 사내지?
Well, forget it. You're a man, you know.
잇키, 메다롯치 따위 없어도 우리가 강하다는 건 안 변해.
Ikki, even without Medarotch, it doesn't change that we are strong.
뭐, 어, 히히. 우리 천재니까.
Well, yeah, heh. We're geniuses after all.
네, 그러세요.
Yeah, good for you.
오늘은 신형 메다롯치 발매일. 다들 지금쯤 사러 갔겠지.
Today is the release date of the new Medarotch. I guess everyone went to get one now.
예약하는 걸 잊어버린 니 탓이다. 포기하셔.
It's your fault for forgetting to preorder. Give up.
그래도 말야, 오늘을 위해서 낭비도 안 하고 용돈 모았단 말야!
But you know, I've saved my allowance without wasting for this day!
안녕하세요.
Good afternoon.
잇키 씨하고 메타비 씨죠?
Mr. Ikki and Mr. Metabee, right?
어.
Yeah.
잇키, 들었어? 우리 유명인이야!
Ikki, did you hear that? We're celebrities!
아, 그래.
Good to know.
저, 잇키 씨하고 메타비 씨를 동경해서 그 동안 아빠한테 하나 사 달라고 했어요!
I admired both of you, Mr. Ikki and Mr. Metabee, so I asked my father to buy one for me!
헤, 들었어, 잇키? 동경한대!
Heh, did you hear that, Ikki! He admires us!
로보틀하고 싶어도, 여름방학이어서 다들 여행가 버려서, 그러니까 그게...
I want to do a Robattle, but since it's a summer vacation period, everyone went to travel and, you know...
좋아! 우리가 로보틀 상대가 되어 줄까!
Great! We'll become your Robattle opponents!
정말로요?!
Really?!
어이어이, 그럴 기분이...
Hey, I'm not in a mood for...
야, 잇키! 언제까지 토라져 있을 거냐! 우린 스타야! 멋진 모습 보여줘야지!
Hey, Ikki! Stop sulking! We are stars! We gotta show them us being cool!
알았어, 알았어!
Oh well then, sure.
상대해 줄게!
We'll take you on!
아싸!
Yay!
이 돌맹이가 땅에 떨어지면 전투 개시다.
When this pebble drops onto the ground, the battle begins.
네!
Yes!
가자!
Let's do this!
코마독! 돌진해!
Comadog! Make a dash!
맡겨멍!
Leave it to me, bark!
메타비! 공중제비 10회!
Metabee! Somersault 10 times!
그건 뭔 작전이냐?
How's that plan supposed to work?
아야!
Ouch!
미안, 미안!
Sorry, sorry!
임마! 날 속였겠다! 똑바로 해, 이 새끼야!
Hey! You deceived me! Do it properly, you brat!
근데 말야, 로보틀 초심자하고 제대로 싸우기도 그렇고...
But you know, it doesn't feel right to fight properly with a Robattle newcomer...
그것도 그렇네. 핸디캡이라도 할까?
That makes sense. Should I be handicapped?
로보틀.
Robattle.
저건 텐료 잇키.
That's Tenryo Ikki.
야, 핸디캡이라고 해도 이건 좀 무식한 거 아냐?
Hey, isn't this handicap too extreme?
믿고 맡겨!
Just leave it to me!
좋아! 로보틀 개시다!
Alright! Begin Robattle!
어, 네!
Uh, got it!
이럇!
Here we go!
코마독! 돌진해!
Comadog! Charge!
빔 발사 준비!
Prepare to fire beam!
빔 발사!
Fire beam!
왼쪽 90도로 크게 점프해!
Jump high 90 degrees to left!
좋아!
Got it!
쫒아, 코마독!
Chase him, Comadog!
그렇구나!
I see!
승부 났네.
The match is set.
물론, 우리 승부다!
Of course, we won.
네 코마독은 고속 주행할 때의 빔의 제일의 무기지?
Your Comadog's strongest weapon is the beam during high speed driving, right?
네.
Yeah.
우리는 모래밭을 써서 그 특기를 봉쇄한 거야.
We used that sandbox to prevent that specialty move.
-그랬구나!
-니가 그걸 지금 알면 어쩌냐!
-So that was what happened!
-You should be knowing that already!
어쨌든 적의 특기가 약점이 될 수도 있다는 거야.
Anyway, the poing is that a specialty move of your enemy can work favorably for you.
그렇구나.
I see.
여러모로 감사했습니다!
Thank you for fighting with me!
그래! 강해져라!
Yeah! Become strong!
네! 안녕히!
Thanks! Bye!
우리 지금 정말 멋졌어!
We were really cool just now!
관전자가 없다는 건 아쉽지만.
Too bad there were no spectators.
내가 봤어.
I saw.
정말 멋졌어.
It really was cool.
미인이네.
She's beautiful.
으, 응. 미녀야. 누굴까.
Y- yeah, she is gorgeous. I wonder who she is.
대단해! 메다로트 파트며 부품이며!
Awesome! Medarot parts and components!
안녕하세요. 처음 뵙겠습니다.
Good afternoon. Nice to meet you.
누나 누구야?
Who are you?
나는 나에. 그냥 잡화상이야. 메다로트 전문.
I am Nae, just a sundries dealer. Specialized in Medarots, that is.
그 얘는 허니, 내 소중한 조수.
That kid is Honey, my precious assistant.
-우린
-알아.
-We are
-I know.
텐료 잇키 군하고 메타비지?
Tenryo Ikki and Metabee, right?
유명인이야! 그래, 너희 생 로보틀을 봤으니, 보답으로 좋아하는 파트 선물해 줄게.
You two are celebrities! I know! As thanks for letting me see your live Robattle, I'll give you a part you like as a present.
정말?! 어디, 어디...
Really?! Let me see...
얘, 신형 메다롯치 못 사서 영 저기압이야.
This guy couldn't buy the new Medarotch and he isn't really feeling well.
그거? 어떻게든 될 거야.
That? I'll get one for you.
정말?!
Really?!
내일까지 기다리면 하나 가져올게.
I'll get one tomorrow.
그래도 그건 비싸니까 선물은 못 해.
But I can't give that as a present since that's pretty expensive.
사요, 사요! 돈은 있어요! 그치!
I'll buy, I'll buy! I have money! Right?!
OK. 그 대신 덤으로 뭐 얹어 줄게. 그게 선물.
OK. But instead, I'll give you an extra. That will be the present.
그럼 내일 올게요!
Then we'll be here tomorrow!
바이바이!
Bye-bye!
안녕!
See ya!
소나기구나.
A sudden evening shower, eh...
기다리고 기다린 신형 메다롯치!
The new Medarotch that we've been waiting for!
겟!
They're ours!
잘 됐네요, 두목!
Good for you, Boss!
어서 신형 메다롯치의 성능을 시험해 보자, 페퍼캣.
Let's test the performance of the new Medarotch, Peppercat.
어?
Huh?
누구냐, 갑자기!
Who did that all of the sudden?!
처음 뵙겠습니다.
Nice to meet you.
(도부로크: 탁주, 막걸리)
(doburoku: unrefined rice wine)
나는 도부로크 초등학교의 데스 메다로터, 긴카이. 인사 대신 로보틀 상대 안 해 주실텨?
I am a Death Medarotter from Doburoku Elementary School, Ginkai. How about a Robattle, to get to know each other?
-데스 메다로터?
-어째요?
-A Death Medarotter?
-What should we do?
괜찮아, 페퍼캣?
Are you okay, Peppercat?
이 정도는 괜찮아요!
That was nothing!
우리 스크류즈에게 로보틀을 신청하다니 좋은 배짱이구나.
Asking for a Robattle against us Screws, eh? You sure have guts.
지금 메다롯치 착용할 테니까 기다려라!
I'm putting on my Medarotch right now, so wait!
싫어.
No.
어?
Huh?
가자, 건 데스페라도!
Let's do this, Gun Desperado!
GDR형 건 데스페라도
GDR Type Gun Desperado
하드 타겟! 데드 장고! 발사 준비!
Hard Target! Dead Django! Prepare to fire!
야야!
Hey, hey!
일제 사격.
Fusillade.
접근해서 메가배럴으로 문병해 줘!
Give her a close look at your Megabarrel!
페퍼캣!
Peppercat!
그만둬! 이미 기능 정지됐어! 내 패배야!
Stop! She stopped working already! I lost!
좋아, 건 데스페라도. 그만둬. 메달을 주워!
Well then. Gun Desperado, stop. Pick up the medal.
어?
What?!
준비도 안 됐는데 공격하다니 비겁해!
Attacking when I wasn't ready to fight is dirty!
메달은 가져간다.
I'll take the medal.
-뭐?!
-그건 룰 위반이야!
-What?!
-That's a violation of rules!
설교는 됐고! 메달을 돌려받고 싶다면 이 마을에서 제일 강한 메다로터를 데리고 와!
Stop talking tediously! If you want the medal back, then take the strongest Medarotter in town to here!
두목, 이 마을에서 제일 강한 놈이라 하면...
Boss, if he wants the strongest one in town...
역시...
That means...
그 녀석을 데려올 수밖에 없군.
We have to take him here.
뭐야, 키쿠히메냐?
Oh, Kikuhime?
메다롯치 자랑이라면 듣고 싶지 않아.
I don't want to hear you bragging about your new Medarotch.
어? 메달을 빼앗겼어? 인질?
What? Someone took your medal as a hostage?
뭔 일이야, 잇키?
What's up, Ikki?
보아하니 우리하고 로보틀하고 싶다는 놈이 있나 봐.
It seems that some guy wants to have a Robattle with us.
바로 오래. 어쩔래?
She wants us there right now. What should we do?
비오잖아.
It's raining...
그렇네... 담에!
You're right... Next time!
패기 없다고? 누가 패기가 없냐!
I'm a coward?! How dare you say I'm a coward!
어? 야, 너, 메타비! 너보고 돌팔이래!
What?! Hey, Metabee! She's saying that you're a quack!
뭐?! 돌팔이?! 가만 듣고 있을 수가 없군!
What?! A quack?! I won't stand listening to this!
온대.
He says that he'll come.
역시 명교섭인!
You're a good negotiator!
아직이냐? 스크류즈 씨들.
Are they here yet, Screws?
지, 지금 오고 있어!
T- they're coming right now!
로보틀 세계 대회 준결승자가 이 마을에 있다니 말야!
To know that the one who took the 2nd place in the World Robattle Championship is in this village...
기대되네!
I'm looking forwards for it!
잇키 놈, 정말 올까요?
I wonder if Ikki will actually come...
걔 지멋대로니까...
He's kinda unpredictable, too...
정말, 잇키도 메타비도 정의감이 있다고는 생각할 수가 없군.
I really don't think neither Ikki or Metabee has a sense of justice, at all.
안 되겠네요.
This isn't good.
어이!
Heya!
안녕이다!
Hi!
누가 패기 없냐?!
Who's a coward?!
누가 돌팔이냐!
Who's a quack?!
그냥 적절한 표현이었어, 적절한 표현!
That was just a figure of speech, you know!
네가 텐료 잇키 씨냐?
So you must be Mr. Tenryo Ikki, eh?
그리고 저 쪽이 메타비겠구나.
And you must be Metabee.
너구나! 이 마을에서 제일 강한 메다로터하고 싸우고 싶다는 건방진 놈이!
So it was you who impertinently wanted to fight against the strongest Medarotter in this village!
팍 갚아 주겠어!
We'll pay you back for this!
에헤, 헤헤, 헤헤헤헿...
Heh, heh, hehehehehehe...
자! 약속은 지켰어! 페퍼캣 메달 돌려줘!
See! I've kept the promise! Give Peppercat's medal back!
쟤들 전혀 안 강해 보이는데, 정말?
They don't look strong, nope. You sure about him?
얼굴 보면 알잖아! 텐료 잇키하고 메타비야! 돌려줘!
You know their face! They're Tenryo Ikki and Metabee! Give it back!
흥, 알았어, 알았어, 돌려줄게!
Hmph! Yeah, yeah! I'll give it back!
자.
Here.
페퍼캣...
Peppercat...
잘 됐네요, 두목!
It worked out, boss!
이와노이, 카가미야마, 바로 페퍼캣 수리다.
Iwanoi, Kagamiyama! Start repairing Peppercat right away!
알았어요!
Roger that!
자, 나머지는 알아서 잘 부탁해!
The rest is up to you!
어, 야, 야! 복수 안 봐?
Um, hey, hey! Aren't you interested in watching the revenge?
어?
Huh?
-젠장!
-뭐야!
-Damn!
-What was that?!
-너 임마!
-더러워, 갑자기 공격이라니!
-You brat!
-Attacking without prior notice is cowardly!
준비, 땅! 하고 시작하는 다툼이 어디 있냐?
I've never heard of a brawl that starts with "ready, go!"
다툼?
A quarrel?
로보틀은 다툼이 아냐! 규칙을 지키고 당당히 싸우는 게 로보틀이야!
A Robottle is not a brawl! Keeping the rules and fighting fairly is Robattle!
아니야. 로보틀은 다툼이야! 쓰러지느냐 쓰러뜨리느냐, 그뿐이다!
No, Robottle is a brawl! To take down or be taken down - that's about it!
너희 로보틀은 소꿉장난에 불과해!
Your Robattle is nothing more than a child's play!
뭐시라?!
What?!
잇키, 쟤한테 진짜 로보틀을 보여주자!
Ikki, let's show him the true Robattle!
좋아, 메타비! 리볼버 발사!
Alright! Metabee, fire revolver!
이랴!
Take this!
메가배럴 발사!
Launch Megabarrel!
접근해서 반응탄이야!
Approach and use your Reactive Bullet!
좋아!
Got it!
이게!
Take this!
데드 장고 발사!
Launch Dead Django!
쟤 뒤로 돌아가!
Go to the back side of that guy!
안 들리냐! 역시 메다롯치가 없으면 안 되는구나!
Can't you hear me? It really isn't working with a Medarotch!
총알 떨어졌구나! 메타비! 반응탄으로 녀석 머리 관절을 노려!
He's out of ammo! Metabee, use your Reactive Bullet and aim to the joint between its head and body!
알았어!
Got it!
어라, 나도 총알 떨어졌어!
Huh, I'm out, too!
탄환 전송.
Transfer bullets.
뭐?!
What?!
어쩌냐, 잇키!
What should we do, Ikki?!
어, 어이! 로보틀 중에 탄환 전송이라니 더럽다!
H- hey! Transferring bullet in the midst of a Robattle is dirty!
충고는 고마우이. 그래도 그 쓸데없는 잘난 척 덕분에 너희들이 지는 거야!
Thanks for your advice, but you're losing because of that boring nobleness of yours!
메가배럴 발사!
Launch Megabarrel!
메타비! 메다포스야!
Metabee! Use Medaforce!
그럴 수밖에 없겠구나!
So that's the only option I have!
메다포스군!
That must be Medaforce!
진짜를 보는 건 처음이야.
It's my first time of seeing the real thing.
안 먹어!
It's not working!
말도 안 돼.
No way.
그게 너희 필살기냐, 메타비 씨인지 뭔지!
Is that your specialty move, Mr. Metabee or Metawhat!
데스 메다로트에게 메다포스는 소용없어!
Medaforce does not work against Death Medarot!
데스 메다로트...
Death Medarot...
건 데스페라도! 끝장내! 메가배럴!
Gun Desperado! Finish this! Megabarrel!
메타비...
Metabee...
메타비!
Metabee!
제기랄! 젠장! 망할!
Damn! Dammit! Damn!
코쿠류! 어딨냐?
Kokuryu! Where are you?
어이, 긴카이. 난 여기에 있어.
Heya, Ginkai. I'm over here.
어때, 데스 메다로트 상태는?
So how's your new Death Medarot?
약한 놈들밖에 없어서 말할 것도 없지.
They're all weaklings and I have nothing to say about 'em.
로보틀 세계 대회 준우승자를 이겼다는데 정말?
I heard that you defeated the 2nd place winner of Robattle World Championship - is that true?
어, 정말이야! 너한테 받은 건 데스페라도 성능 덕분이야!
Yeah, that's true, all thanks to the performance of Gun Desperado you gave to me!
장난감이 아냐. 정말 진짜... 진짜 병기같아!
It's not a toy. It is... it really is like a real weapon!
그래도 아직 안심하긴 일러.
But it's still to early to relax.
어?
Huh?
들은 바에 따르면 텐료 잇키인가 하는 걔, 메다롯치가 없었다나 뭐라나.
According to what I've heard, that Tenryo Ikki guy didn't have his Medarotch with him.
방심은 금물이야!
Don't let your guards down!
어쨌든 이겼잖아! 그런 얼간이 놈들한테!
Anyway, I won! Those idiots are nothing!
물론 긴카이 군의 실력은 믿고 있어. 정말로.
Of course, I'm believing in your abilities, Ginkai. Really.
공짜야. 네가 지지 않으면 좋겠어.
However, I don't want you to not lose...
메다로트 사의 메다로트 따위에게 말야.
...to those Medarots of Medarot Company.
그래! 건 데스페라도 탄환 떨어졌지?
Oh, right! Gun Desperado has used all its bullets, right?
저거 전부 줄게!
You can have all of them!
전부?!
All?!
어. 그러니까, 내일도 잘 부탁해, 긴카이 군.
Yeah. That's why you should keep up with good job tomorrow too, Ginkai.
로보틀의 참된 즐거움을 모두에게 알려 줘.
Teach everybody about the true joy of Robattles.
규칙 따위 필요없는 즐거움을 말야.
The joy of having no rules, that is.
어제 진 거 아직도 신경쓰이냐, 잇키?
Is yesterday's defeat still bothering you, Ikki?
응.
Yeah.
규칙을 안 지키는 짝퉁 메다로터한테 졌을 뿐이잖아!
You have lost to a fake Medarotter who doesn't abide by the rules!
나라면 봐봐! 씽씽하다!
Look at me! I'm all good!
분해. 메다롯치만 있었으면...
I'm mortified. Only if I had my Medarotch...
나에 씨가 곧 올 거야. 메다롯치 가지고.
Ms. Nae will be here soon with the Medarotch you wanted.
잇키 씨! 메타비 씨!
Mr. Ikki! Mr. Metabee!
어? 어제 소년!
Huh? The boy from yesterday!
큰일이에요. 빨리 와 주세요!
This is bad! Please come with me right now!
이상한 메다로터가 나타나서 날뛰고 있어요!
A strange Medarotter has appeared and is raging!
그 놈 설마...
Could that guy be...
피스톨 머리 걔?
The one with pistol head?
맞아요!
That's right!
-가자, 메타비!
-흥, 당연하지!
-Let's go, Metabee!
-Hmph, of course!
이쪽이에요!
This way!
잇키 군!
Ikki!
어, 나에 씨!
Hey, Ms. Nae!
브라스!
Brass!
이제 그만해!
Please stop!
이것만 있다면!
This will just do!
약속한 덤. 메타비에게 새 파트를 선물할게.
These are the extra I promised. I'm giving Metabee new parts as a present.
나, 이대로 괜찮은데...
I'm fine as I am right now...
신형 KBT야. 메타비에게 잘 어울린다 생각해.
It's a new KBT type. I think it goes well on you, Metabee.
어쨌든 서두르자, 메타비!
Anyway, let's hurry, Metabee!
건 데스페라도, 메가배럴로 산산조각내버려!
Gun Desperado, dissect that with Megabarrel!
멈춰라!
Stop!
복수하러 왔다, 긴카이인지 뭐시기인지!
I'm here to get my revenge, Ginkai or Ginwhat!
잇키!
Ikki!
또 왔냐? 어제는 막 당한 주제에!
You're here again? You were so badly done yesterday!
흥! 우리는 재기가 빨라!
Hmph! We are quick in recovery!
나에 씨에게 받은 새 파트를 쓰자, 메타비!
Let's use the new parts that Ms. Nae gave us, Metabee!
-좋아! 어, 지금?!
-그 파트를 집에 보내버리겠어!
-Right! Wait, now?!
-I'm sending your current parts home!
전송!
Transfer!
으아, 새 파트는 메다롯치에 프로그램되어있지 않아서 전송으로 장착할 수가 없나 봐!
Err, the new parts aren't programmed in the Medarotch, so I can't transfer and install them at once!
정말이냐!
Was that it?!
손으로 장착할 수밖에 없어.
We gotta install it by hand.
바보네...
Idiots...
이게 오른팔 파트지?
Is this the right arm part?
멍청아! 그건 머리야!
Idiot! That's the head!
어, 그럼 이건?
Oh, then what about this?
음, 잠깐만. 그건, 그건...
Uh, let me see. That's... that's...
어디야! 야!
Where is it?! Hey!
정말 긴장감 없는 놈들이군...
How can they be so easy-going...
-잠깐, 너!
-잠깐이라니!
-Wait, you!
-Why would I wait?!
건 데스페라도! 녀석을 조준해!
Gun Desperado! Aim at him!
-봐봐, 잠깐!
-왜?
-Hey, just a moment!
-Why?!
자, 딱 잘 됐네.
It's just good now.
서둘러!
Hurry!
데드 장고! 위협 발사!
Dead Django! Give them a warning shot!
메타비!
Metabee!
오래 기다렸겠다! 새 메타비 등장이다!
Sorry for the wait! The new Metabee is here!
신 KBT형 메타비
New KBT Type Metabee
새 메타비?
The new Metabee?
메가배럴, 발사!
Launch Megabarrel!
쟨 몇이고 탄환을 쓸 수 있어. 뒤로 돌아가서 공격할 수 밖에 없는데 어쩌냐!
That guy can use bullets as much as he wants. The only thing Metabee can do is to go to its back and attack, but how?
어?
Huh?
메다체인지? 뭐야, 이게?
Medachange? What's this?
그렇구나! 주행 모드구나!
I see! Driving Mode!
메다체인지! 레클리스 모드!
Medachange! Reckless Mode!
메다체인지? 음, 어, 이거?
Medachange? Let's see.... is this it?
뭐야?!
What?!
이, 이게!
T-This is it!
변형했어!
He transformed!
건 데스페라도! 뒤야!
Gun Desperado! On your back!
이 자식!
You bastard!
흥!
Hmph!
말도 안 돼!
No way!
메타비 승!
Metabee won!
강해!
He's strong!
전송.
Transfer.
이대로라면 미안하니까! 난 코쿠류가 함께해!
This is not over! Kokuryu's with me!
코쿠류? 누구냐, 걘?
Kokuryu? Who the heck is that?
나, 이 파트 마음에 들어!
I think I like these parts!
그래, 이따가 나에 씨에게 지금 전투 자세히 알려 줘야지!
Yeah! I'm going to tell Ms. Nae about the battle we just had!
규칙 위반하는 데스 메다로터. 흥! 나와 메타비가 언제라도 상대해 주겠어!
Death Medaroters who do not abide by rules... Metabee and I will face them whenever they want to!
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday all of a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rang
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
You are so much older than me, it makes me sad
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun to admire from afar?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't let it get to you
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
레클리스 모드에의 메다체인지를 해낸 메타비!
Metabee has achieved Medachange to Reckless Mode!
그러나 그 반동으로 긴급 수리가 필요해졌다.
But as a recoil of that, he needs an emergency repair.
구형 바디에 돌아가고 만 메타비에게 코쿠류가 조종하는 데스 메다로트, 탱크댕크의 마의 손이 뻗친다.
Metabee had to go back to his old body, but Kokuryu's Death Medarot, Tankdank's evil hands are onto him.
수리 완료까지 앞으로 24시간.
24 hours until the repair gets done.
과연 메타비와 잇키는 이기긴 할 수 있을 것인가?
Will Metabee and Ikki manage to win at least?
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 금지된 싸움!
Next time on Medarot: Spirits! Forbidden Battle!
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!